Guide to the James Joyce collection, [ca. 1893]-1941
Joyce, James collection, [ca. 1893]-1941
- Series I. Manuscripts
  - Exiles, Spring 1918; 4609 Bd Ms 4 +++ [?]
    32 leaves. Galley proofs of the Grant Richards edition. These proofs are printed on sheets of poor-quality laid paper. They begin with page 3 of the book and continue through page 137. This is evidently an extra set of proofs, not used for corrections. Scholes 53.
  - Italiano, ca. 1904; 4609 Bd Ms 5 +
    James Joyce's workbook in Italian and German. These autograph writings are in a large notebook, bound in half cloth over brown-and-black boards, with marbled edges. On the front cover is pasted a large label with the word "Italiano" in Joyce's hand. The book consists of 138 leaves of unruled white wove paper. The first part of the notebook is a workbook in Italian combined with a commonplace book in Italian. There are 16 leaves of German-English vocabulary before the last, blank, leaf. Scholes 37. ca. 1904 and continued for several years.
  - Advance notice of an exhibition and sale of books and mss. left by James Joyce to be held at The Librairie-Galerie, Oct. 25, 1949; 4609 Bd Ms 6
    This sale notice is typed on 6 large leaves. It contains a detailed description of sale items separated into four categories: Manuscript notes, the Works of Joyce, A Working Library, and Family Portraits. Not in Scholes.
  - A notebook of Stanislaus Joyce, 1936-1943; 4609 Bd Ms 7
    A series of random jottings. This autograph manuscript is in a notebook, bound in half cloth over red-blue-and-gray-marbled boards with marbled edges. The book consists of 100 ruled leaves partially numbered by James Joyce for the "Trade" section of his notes on banking (see Bd. Ms. 2 and Scholes 38). The recto of the unruled end paper bears the title "Trade" and the rectos of the following 6 pages, numbered 1-6, contain James Joyce's notes on this subject. Stanislaus's jottings begin on the recto of the eighth leaf and are continued for 66 pages on 33 leaves. Scholes 63.
  - "James Joyce." By John Francis Byrne, Apr. 1959; ?
    Ithaca. On tape. A lecture given at the Cornell Festival of Contemporary Arts. Not in Scholes. Formerly listed as 4609 Bd Ms+ 115, maybe in collection #11-8-771.
- Series II. Documents and Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Drawing of coat of arms of Ireland, with commentary, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Pen and ink drawing of the Arms of Ireland with notes, possibly in James Joyce's hand. Scholes 1439.
  - Listing of articles published in Il Piccolo della Sera, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 2)
    1 leaf. A list of Joyce's contributions to this Triestine journal. The list of articles, in Stanislaus Joyce's hand, is on one side of a leaf of white wove paper, with scalloped upper edge. Scholes 39.
  - Title page (paper cover) of Ibsen's Digte, Copenhagen, 1891 autographed by Joyce, [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 3)
    1 leaf. This title page from Ibsen's Digte is signed "JasAJoyce" in upper right corner. Scholes 1437.
  - Printed form announcing the enclosure of a cheque to James Joyce, Apr. 7, 1900; D (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Written in 11 Henrietta Street, London. 1 leaf. To James Joyce, a printed form announcing the enclosure of a cheque (for 12/12/0), for his contribution to the Fortnightly Review for April 1900. Signed Hayward. Scholes 511.
  - Unidentified fragment of a letter addressed to Joyce by a friend of Lady Gregory., 1902; AL (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Written in Paris. 1 leaf. Fragment of a letter from a friend of Lady Gregory to James Joyce, offering advice on living in Paris. Scholes 1447.
  - Matriculation certificate, Royal University of Ireland, Sept. 30, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Written in Dublin. 1 leaf. Matriculation certificate of the Royal University of Ireland. States that James Joyce passed the Matriculation Examination in June 1899 and obtained second-class honors in Latin. Signed J.A.Joyce." on verso. Scholes 1374.
  - Ticket admitting James Joyce to the conferring of degrees, Royal University of Ireland. [card], Oct. 31, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Written in Dublin. 1 leaf. Ticket to a public meeting of the Royal University of Ireland for the conferring of degrees. Scholes 1381.
  - Clipping from Irish Times on Feis Ceoil singing competition [newspaper clipping], May 17, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Written in Dublin. 1 leaf. Clipping from the Irish Times of an article on the Feis Ceoil singing competition in which Joyce took third place. The paragraphs that mention Joyce are marked with a box. Scholes 1388.
  - Telegram to Joyce, from unidentified sender reading "Impossible get advance", Oct. 14, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Written in Dublin. 1 leaf. "Joyce" written on verso in blue crayon. Scholes 1449.
  - Newspaper clipping advertising instruction in English at the Berlitz School, taught by James Joyce, Il Giornaletto di Pola, Oct. 31, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Written in Pola. 1 leaf. Scholes 1389.
  - Contract with Grant Richards for publication of Dubliners, Feb. 26, 1906; D (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Written in Trieste. 1 leaf. Signed by Grant Richards. Scholes 1394.
  - Certificate of birth-Giorgio Joyce, Jul. 28, 1906; D (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Written in Trieste. 1 leaf. Scholes 1376.
  - Bill relating to the birth of Lucia Joyce, Ospitale Civico, Trieste, Aug. 5, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Written in Trieste. I leaf. Scholes 1414.
  - Contract for Volta Theatre project, ca. 1909; D (Box 3, Folder 14)
    1 leaf. Contract in Italian for the Volta Theatre project of James Joyce, Giuseppe Caris, Giovanni Rebez, Caterina Machnich (a typed copy, unsigned, undated). Scholes 1404.
  - Newspaper clipping-"Remarkable Romance", 1909 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    1 leaf. Written in Galway [?]. "Naming no names, but obviously the story of James and Nora and their flight to the Continent."- George Healey. Not in Scholes.
  - Dubliners contract, August 19, 1909; DS (Box 3, Folder 16)
    2 leaves. Contract with Maunsel and Co. for publication of Dubliners. Signed George Roberts and James Joyce. Scholes 1395.
  - Listing of expenses for the Volta Theatre, 1909-1910; AD (Box 3, Folder 17)
    1 leaf. List in James Joyce's hand of expenses for the Volta Theatre. Dated December, January, February. Scholes 1405.
  - Theatre Programme announcement of forthcoming publication of Dubliners, Abbey Theatre, Dublin, Sept.- Oct. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    6 leaves. Written in Dublin. Announcement reads, " DUBLINERS, By JAMES JOYCE. 3s. 6d. Net. (Ready in September)." Scholes 1382.
  - Programma per il XII anno accademico, Universita Popolare Triestina, Instituto municipale [program], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    12 leaves. Written in Trieste. Program of the Universita Popolare Triestina for its twelfth academic year (November 5, 1911 to March 31, 1912) in which are scheduled two lectures by Prof. J. Joyce: "Verismo ed idealismo nella letteratura inglese (Daniele De Foe-William Blake). Scholes 1383.
  - Certificate of vaccination, Giorgio Joyce, Oct. 12, 1911; D (Box 3, Folder 20)
    1 leaf. Written in Trieste. Scholes 1378.
  - "A Bi-Centenary Ode" by Oliver St. John Gogarty, [newspaper clipping], July 5, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    2 leaves. Written in Dublin. Clipping from an unidentified newspaper of an article on the bicentenary celebrations of Trinity College Medical School and an ode written for the occasion by Oliver St. John Gogarty. Scholes 1390.
  - Report cards from the Civica Scuola Popolare E Cittadina in Trieste, July 15, 1912 and 1913; D (Box 3, Folder 22)
    2 leaves. Written in Trieste. Scholes 1379.
  - Printed ticket of admission to a series of ten lectures in English by Joyce on "Amleto di G. Shakespeare", Nov. 4, 1912- (Box 3, Folder 23)
    1 leaf. Written in Trieste. Scholes 1384.
  - Extracts from press notices and reviews of Dubliners [pamphlet], 1914 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    6 leaves. Grant Richards, London. 3 copies (2 green, same font, 1 pink, different font, but identical text). Scholes 1391.
  - Contract with Grant Richards for the publication of Dubliners, Mar. 20, 1914; D (Box 3, Folder 25)
    1 leaf. Written in Trieste. Signed by Grant Richards. Scholes 1396.
  - Bill sent to James Joyce from Triestine bookseller, F.H. Schimpff, May 23, 1914; D (Box 3, Folder 26)
    1 leaf. Written in Trieste. Bill listing twenty books purchased by James Joyce from September 1913 to May 1914. Scholes 1401.
  - Memorandum of agreement making J.B. Pinker agent for James Joyce's literary work, Apr. 1915; D (Box 3, Folder 27)
    1 leaf. Written in Trieste. Signed by James Brand Pinker. Scholes 1398.
  - Memorandum of agreement making J.B. Pinker agent for Joyce's dramatic work, Apr. 5, 1915; D (Box 3, Folder 28)
    1 leaf. Written in Trieste. Signed by James Brand Pinker. Scholes 1397.
  - Extracts from press notices and reviews of A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man [pamphlet], 1916 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    8 leaves. Written in London, New York. The four pamphlets are entitled, "Extracts from Continental Press Notices," "Extracts from American Press Notices," "Extra Press Notices," and "Extract from Press Notices." Scholes 1391.
  - Listing of periodicals in which reviews of A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man appeared, ca. 1917; AD (Box 3, Folder 30)
    1 leaf. A list of 11 periodicals in which reviews of Portrait appeared. Dated February to September 1917. Scholes 1440.
  - Contract with Grant Richards for the publication of Exiles, Aug. 31, 1917; D (Box 3, Folder 31)
    2 leaves. Written in Zurich. Signed by Grant Richards. With typed carbon copy of extra clauses inserted by James Joyce in the "Exiles" agreement. Scholes 1399.
  - Extracts from press notices and reviews of Exiles [pamphlet], 1918 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    2 leaves. Written in London, New York. Scholes 1391.
  - Group of papers relating to the 1918-1919 lawsuit between Joyce and Henry Carr, Oct. 1918-Mar. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    10 leaves. Written in Zurich. In German. Scholes 1409.
  - Notice of proclamation of Irish Republic [newspaper clipping], Jan. 22, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    1 leaf. Written in Zurich. In German. Scholes 1392.
  - Copies of statements signed by Joyce regarding the lawsuit between Joyce and Henry Carr, Apr. 28, 1919; DS (Box 3, Folder 35)
    20 leaves. Written in Zurich. Four copies in English, two in German. Scholes 1408.
  - Bill sent to James Joyce from Leipzig bookseller, Simmel and Co., Apr. 20, 1920; D (Box 3, Folder 36)
    1 leaf. Written in Leipzig. Bill listing five books purchased by James Joyce from "antiquarisch aus Katalog 229." Scholes 1402.
  - "Un Singolare Scrittore Irlandes" [newspaper clipping], Aug. 23, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    1 leaf. Clipping from Il Mondo of an article on James Joyce by F. Paolo Giordani. Scholes 1393.
  - Printed announcement of a lecture to be given by Valery Larbaud, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    1 leaf. Written in Paris. Sponsored by La Maison des Amis des Livres for Joyce's benefit on Dec. 7. Scholes 1385.
  - Typed listing of signatures protesting Samuel Roth's pirating of Ulysses, ca. Jan. 13, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    1 leaf. Written in Paris. Some names added in ink. Envelope addressed to Stanislaus Joyce in James Joyce's hand. Scholes 1411.
  - Typed list of signatures protesting Samuel Roth's pirating of Ulysses, ca. Jan. 20, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    1 leaf. Written in Paris. Additional names added in ink; with envelope addressed to Stanislaus Joyce in James Joyce's hand. List longer than that of box 3, folder 39 above. Scholes 1412.
  - Printed listing of signatures, with statement of intent, protesting Samuel Roth's pirating of Ulysses, Feb. 2, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    1 leaf. Written in Paris. Printed protest including printed list of 167 signatures. Scholes 1413.
  - Typed report on the condition of Joyce's eyes, Sept. 7, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    1 leaf. Written in Paris. with envelope. Typed report on the results of an exam of his eyes, sent by James Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce. Scholes 1442.
  - Printed program for concert, Morley College Concert Society, May 27, 1948-9 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    1 leaf. Written in London. Among selections is composition by Matyas Seiber, "Ulysses" for solo tenor, chorus and orchestra, based on texts by Joyce. Not in Scholes.
  - Italian influences on James Joyce [anonymous], ca. 1950; TM (Box 3, Folder 44)
    54 leaves. Notes and chapters relating to a thesis on Italian influences on James Joyce, probably prepared under the direction of Stanislaus Joyce, with some corrections in his hand and some in an unidentified hand. Scholes 1445.
  - Publisher's announcement re forthcoming publication of Ellmann's biography, James Joyce, ca. 1959 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    1 leaf. Entitled "Why this is the book on James Joyce." Includes order form. Not in Scholes.
  - Stephen D, Hugh Leonard [theatre program], Aug. 3, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    For production by Olney Theatre, Olney, Maryland. Gift of Giles F. Shepherd, Aug. 16, 1966. Not in Scholes.
  - Newspaper clipping from N.Y. Times announcing death of Mary Kathleen (Joyce) Monaghan, Dec. 13, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    1 leaf. Not in Scholes.
  - Program of the First James Joyce Symposium. Dublin. Ireland., June 15-16, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Written in Dublin. 2 copies. Not in Scholes.
  - ReJoyce [theatre program], Feb. 1976 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    For readings from Joyce adapted by Dan Laurence and presented at Incarnate Word College Reader's Theatre. With news clipping on the production from San Antonio Express-News, Feb. 28, 1976. Gift of Bernard F. Burgunder. Not in Scholes.
- Series III. Outgoing Correspondence
  - March 1901-December 1905
    - Oliver St. John Gogarty (1 copy of a letter) (Box 4)
    - Henrik Ibsen (1 draft of a letter) (Box 4)
    - John Stanislaus Joyce (7 letters) (Box 4)
    - Dublin family (1 letter) (Box 4)
    - Mary Jane Joyce (10 letters) (Box 4)
    - Nora Joyce (19 letters) (Box 4)
    - Stanislaus Joyce (47 letters) (Box 4)
    - Secretary of the Academy of Music (1 letter) (Box 4)
  - July 1906-August 1911
    - Stanislaus Joyce (82 letters) (Box 5)
    - John Stanislaus Joyce (l letter) (Box 5)
    - Grant Richards (1 letter, draft) (Box 5)
    - Nora Joyce (37 letters) (Box 5)
    - Joseph Hone (1 letter) (Box 5)
    - Maunsel & Co., Dublin (1 letter) (Box 5)
    - Letter "to the editor" regarding Dubliners (1 letter) (Box 5)
  - April 1912-January 1941
    - William A. Bradley (l letter, between July and December 1920) (Box 4)
    - Stanislaus Joyce (88 letters) (Box 6)
    - Eileen Joyce (1 letter) (Box 6)
    - Nora Joyce (7 letters) (Box 6)
    - Maunsel & Co. (1 letter, copy) (Box 6)
    - Ralph Busser (1 letter) (Box 6)
    - Harriet Monroe (1 letter) (Box 6)
    - Ernest Boyd (3 letters, copies) (Box 6)
    - Sir Horace Rumbold, British Minister (1 copy) (Box 6)
    - Nathalie Barney (1 letter) (Box 6)
    - Ezra Loomis Pound (1 letter) (Box 6)
    - C. Huntington (1 letter, copy) (Box 6)
- Series IV. Incoming Correspondence, Manuscripts and Documents
  - Alphabetical name index, A-F
    - Richard Aldington (Box 7)
    - George Allen & Unwin, Ltd. (Box 7)
    - Anglo-French Review (Box 7)
    - William Archer (8 letters) (Box 7)
    - Rejection slip for Dubliners, from Edward Arnold (Box 7)
    - Ebba Atterbom (Box 7)
    - A. Auvergniot (Box 7)
    - W.A.B (Box 7)
    - Louis Bagnan [to J.B. Pinker?] (Box 7)
    - John Baillie (Box 7)
    - Mrs. Thomas Barnacle to Nora Joyce (3 letters) (Box 7)
    - Sylvia Beach to Stanislaus Joyce (5 letters) (Box 7)
    - Silvio Benco (Box 7)
    - Berlitz Schools of Languages (Box 7)
    - RAB [Richard A. Best?] (Box 7)
    - Bill for eyeglasses, Bial & Freund (Box 7)
    - Augustine Birrell to Ezra Pound (Box 7)
    - Biver and Co. (Box 7)
    - William Blackmore (Box 7)
    - Carl Bleibtreu (Box 7)
    - Nicco [?] Bliznakoff (Box 7)
    - Vela Bliznakoff (Box 7)
    - Marionne L. Bloom (Box 7)
    - Board of Education, London (Box 7)
    - Fratelli Bocca (Box 7)
    - Paul Bompard (Box 7)
    - Georges Borach (Box 7)
    - X.M. Boulestin (Box 7)
    - Ernest A. Boyd (Box 7)
    - Frank Budgen (5 letters) (Box 7)
    - Ferruccio Busoni (Box 7)
    - O'Brien Butler (Box 7)
    - Chateau de Lancy (Box 7)
    - Muriel Ciolkowska (2) (Box 7)
    - City of Dundee Prisoners of War Help Committee (Box 7)
    - James Midgley Clark (2) (Box 7)
    - Sir Arthur Clutton-Brock to Ezra Pound (1) and to James Joyce (2) (Box 7)
    - Richard Cobden-Sanderson (Box 7)
    - Padraic Colum (2) (Box 7)
    - Memorandum from the Consorzio Industriale di Mutui Prestiti (4) (Box 7)
    - Archibald Constable and Co. (2) (Box 7)
    - W.F. Cope (Box 7)
    - Corporation of Dublin (Box 7)
    - Corriere della Sera (Box 7)
    - Mary Corse (Box 7)
    - Vincent Cosgrave (Box 7)
    - Edvige Constantini (2) (Box 7)
    - William Courteney Leonard (Fortnightly Review) (5) (Box 7)
    - Gretta Cousins (Box 7)
    - James H. Cousins (Box 7)
    - Constantine Curran (5) (Box 7)
    - George Healey from Constantine Curran (Box 7)
    - Emma Cuzzi (2) (Box 7)
    - Daily Express (Box 7)
    - Giovanni Dal Min (Box 7)
    - J. Wilfred Davies (2) (Box 7)
    - George S. Dempsey (Box 7)
    - Leone Dario de Tuoni (Box 7)
    - Juda de Vries (alias Jules Martin) (12) (Box 7)
    - Arnold Dolmetsch (Box 7)
    - Joseph Douce (4) (Box 7)
    - C.M. Doyle (Box 7)
    - Invoices from Dublin Woolen Co. (22) (Box 7)
    - Dublin Woolen Co. (6) (Box 7)
    - D.N. Dunlop and Co. (Box 7)
    - Daniel Egan (2) (Box 7)
    - Piet Endt (2) (Box 7)
    - Wilhelm Engele (Box 7)
    - Siegmund Feilbogen (Box 7)
    - Ettore Fileti and Co. (Box 7)
    - Alessandro Francini-Bruni (Box 7)
    - Nora Joyce from Clothilde Francini (Box 7)
    - J.O. Francis (Box 7)
  - Alphabetical name index, G - Joyce, Helen
    - George V., King of Great Britain via his Private Secretary (Box 8)
    - C. Georges-Bazile (Box 8)
    - Charles Ghezzi (Box 8)
    - Schema for Ulysses, Stuart Gilbert [copy] (Box 8)
    - E. Gilford (Box 8)
    - Louis Gillet [fragment] (Box 8)
    - Bill from London bookseller, Henry W. Glover (Box 8)
    - Oliver St. John Gogarty (24 letters & documents) (Box 8)
    - Maud Gonne (Box 8)
    - Sir Edmund William Gosse to W.B. Yeats (1) and James Joyce (1) (Box 8)
    - Great Britain, Consulate General, Zurich to James Joyce (4) to C.W. Sykes (2) (Box 8)
    - Great Britain, Vice-Consulate, Basel (Box 8)
    - Richard John Greenham (Box 8)
    - Greening and Co. (Box 8)
    - Lady Augusta Gregory (5 letters) (Box 8)
    - Padric Gregory (Box 8)
    - Frank Gschwindig (Box 8)
    - Fanny Guillermet (Box 8)
    - Bridget H. (Box 8)
    - Felix E. Hackett to Miss Power (Box 8)
    - Edmund J Healy to Oliver St. John Gogarty [copy] (Box 8)
    - Michael Healy (12) (Box 8)
    - Jane Heap (2) (Box 8)
    - W.A. Henderson (2) (Box 8)
    - Katherine Tynan Hinkson (Box 8)
    - Joseph M. Hone (2) (Box 8)
    - W.T.H. Howe (Box 8)
    - Ben W. Huebsch (10) (Box 8)
    - C. Huntington (Box 8)
    - Incorporated Society of Authors, Playwrights and Composers (4) (Box 8)
    - Incorporated Stage Society to Mr. Sturge Moore (Box 8)
    - Irish Homestead Irish Times (2) (Box 8)
    - Amilie Jarnach to Nora Joyce (Box 8)
    - Philip Jarnach (2) (Box 8)
    - Charles Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (23) (Box 8)
    - Charles Joyce to James Joyce (12) (Box 8)
    - Eileen Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (6) (Box 8)
    - Eva Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (9) (Box 8)
    - Eva Joyce to Nora Joyce (Box 8)
    - Eva Joyce to Eileen Joyce (2) (Box 8)
    - Florrie Joyce to Eva Joyce (Box 8)
    - Giorgio Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (5) (Box 8)
    - Helen Kastor Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (2) (Box 8)
  - Alphabetical name index, Joyce, John Stanislaus - Joyce, Nora
    - John Stanislaus Joyce to James Joyce (5) (Box 9)
    - John Stanislaus Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (22) (Box 9)
    - Documents relative to registration of birth of Lucia Joyce (Box 9)
    - Scholastic record for 1913-1914, Lucia Joyce (Box 9)
    - Lucia Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (8) (Box 9)
    - Lucia Joyce to Mrs. Herbert Hughes (3) (Box 9)
    - Mabel Joyce (Baby) to Stanislaus Joyce (5) (Box 9)
    - Margaret Alice Joyce (Poppie) to Stanislaus Joyce (6) (Box 9)
    - Mary Jane Joyce (6) (Box 9)
    - Nora Joyce (20) (Box 9)
    - Nora Joyce to Stanislaus Joyce (4) (Box 9)
    - Nora Joyce to Eileen Joyce (Box 9)
    - Nora Joyce to May Joyce (Box 9)
    - Nora Joyce to Mrs. Herbert Hughes (2) (Box 9)
  - Alphabetical name index, Joyce, Stanislaus - K
    - Commonplace Book, Stanislaus Joyce (Box 10)
    - Stanislaus Joyce to Josephine Murray [draft] (Box 10)
    - Memoirs, Stanislaus Joyce [fragment] [copy] (Box 10)
    - Notebook, "Selections in Prose from Various Authors," Stanislaus Joyce (Box 10)
    - Notebook, "Selections in Verse from Various Authors," Stanislaus Joyce (Box 10)
    - Notes on English Literature, Stanislaus Joyce (Box 10)
    - "Shaw's pre-war plays," Stanislaus Joyce [?] (Box 10)
    - Pay voucher, Stanislaus Joyce (Box 10)
    - Stanislaus Joyce to Josephine Murray (Box 10)
    - Stanislaus Joyce to James Joyce (28) (Box 10)
    - Stanislaus Joyce to Nora Joyce (9) (Box 10)
    - Thomas Kelly (5) (Box 10)
    - Mary S. Kettle (Box 10)
    - Mary S. Kettle to Israel Kaplan (Box 10)
    - Thomas M. Kettle (3) (Box 10)
    - Bill from Kuoni (Box 10)
    - Kuoni (Box 10)
  - Alphabetical name index, L - Ph
    - K. Lee (Box 11)
    - L. Lerouin [Levouin ?] (Box 11)
    - John George Lidwell (2) (Box 11)
    - Carlo Linati (7) (Box 11)
    - Little, Brown and Co. to John Quinn (Box 11)
    - David Lloyd-George to Claud W. Sykes [copy] (Box 11)
    - John Long (4) (Box 11)
    - E.V. Longworth (2) (Box 11)
    - Dr. M. Lothar to Dr. George Seybel (2) (Box 11)
    - D.A. Luzzato (Box 11)
    - George A. MacGinty (2) (Box 11)
    - Edith McCormick (8) (Box 11)
    - Harold F. McCormick (Box 11)
    - Stephen MacKenna (Box 11)
    - William K. Magee (4) (Box 11)
    - E. St. Lo Malet to James Joyce (2) and to the Secretary of Incorporated Society of Authors (1) (Box 11)
    - B. Marper [sp.?] (Box 11)
    - Edward Howard Marsh (2) (Box 11)
    - Elkin Mathews to Arthur Symons (Box 11)
    - Elkin Mathews (19) (Box 11)
    - Rev. Charles H. Matthews (Box 11)
    - Maunsel and Co. (Box 11)
    - Albert E. Medcalf [copy] (2) (Box 11)
    - Henry Louis Mencken (3) (Box 11)
    - D. C. Merogge (Box 11)
    - Hannah von Mettal (Box 11)
    - Ministero Dell'Instruzionem Consiglio Superiore, Rome (2) (Box 11)
    - Giovanni Moggi (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to George Harris Healey (6) (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to Stanislaus Joyce (13) (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to James Joyce (8) (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to Eileen Joyce (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to Nora Joyce (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to Ulick O'Connor [copy] (Box 11)
    - Mary Kathleen Monaghan (Joyce) to Israel Kaplan (13) (Box 11)
    - Monroe, Saw and Co (13) (Box 11)
    - Harriet Monroe (3) (Box 11)
    - Gina Montressor (Box 11)
    - T. Sturge Moore (Box 11)
    - Dom Germain Morin (Box 11)
    - T.E. Morton (Box 11)
    - Alice Murray to Stanislaus Joyce (Box 11)
    - Charles J. Murray (Box 11)
    - Kathleen Murray (Katsie) to Stanislaus Joyce (5) (Box 11)
    - Josephine Murray to James Joyce (14) (Box 11)
    - Josephine Murray to Nora Joyce (2) (Box 11)
    - Josephine Murray to Stanislaus Joyce (12) (Box 11)
    - Nast-Kolb and Schumacher (6) (Box 11)
    - Owen Nugent (2) (Box 11)
    - Aldo Oberdorfer (Box 11)
    - Oesterheld and Co. (Box 11)
    - Carrol N. O'Sullivan to John S. Joyce (1) and to Dr. Birmingham (1) (Box 11)
    - Cecil Clifford Palmer (Box 11)
    - Geoffrey Molyneux Palmer (8) (Box 11)
    - Benedetto Palmieri (Box 11)
    - Pathe Freres, London (2) (Box 11)